Bryan Turner

Software Engineer

bryan.turner.ch@gmail.com | 720-476-2698 | Github: bryturner | LinkedIn: /in/bryanturnerdev

SUMMARY

A recent graduate of a Java full stack apprenticeship with experience using Angular and React in conjunction with SQL and NoSQL databases. Has a passion for finding creative solutions to complex problems and a constant drive to grow as a developer. Proven ability to collaborate effectively with team members and build positive relationships with clients and colleagues.

SKILLS

> Angular

Java

Spring Boot

> React

> MongoDB

➤ Git/Github

> TypeScript/JavaScript

> PostgreSQL

Docker

> HTML/CSS

> NodeJS

> AWS Cloud Practitioner

WORK HISTORY

Associate Full Stack Software Developer & Consultant - York Solutions

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

- Expanded technical knowledge through project based learning and collaboration with peers
- Led sub-cohort group backend team in designing projects utilizing Java Spring Boot and Angular

Owner/Self-Employed - Just Smile International

Mar 2017 - Oct 2022

- Expanded business across multiple e-commerce platforms with an annual growth rate of 75%+
- Provided excellent customer service with 1000+ customers giving 100% positive feedback rating

Teacher - International School of Zurich North

Aug 2015 - Jan 2017

- Facilitated school-wide adoption of assessment software resulting in increased grading efficiency
- Designed entire IT curriculum including graphic design, HTML and CSS, 3D modeling and logic

PROJECTS

Pantry App Capstone – Github Links: FE | BE

Created full stack app using Java Spring Boot and Angular that allows users to create a personal
account, add items to a shared pantry and create, view, and use personalized recipes

Compare Grocery Product Prices – Page Link | Github Link

 Built a full-stack app from start to finish using the MERN stack that lets users compare grocery prices and save products on a grocery or favorites list

Gardening Weather and Air Quality App – Page Link | Github Link

 Designed responsive page that gives users recommendations about when to garden based on the weather utilizing CSS design skills and JavaScript OOP and MVC patterns

EDUCATION

Fort Lewis College - Durango, Colorado

Bachelor of Arts in Education with Cultural and Linguistic Diversity Endorsement